Hey! Come on,
Mouse, out of the water!
Oh, Mama. A little longer.
- I said out! Right now!
You're both completely blue!
They're pretty.
- Who are they?
The Shah of Iran and his wife.
- Ah, my three Graces.
Papa, what is a Shah?
- Sort of like a king.
A Shah may cut off the
head of anyone he dislikes.
Don't tell the children such rubbish.
- The Truth is Simple.
With such power, there is no joke.
- Hallo, Klaus.
And? How goes the Revolution?
- Right now, it's on holiday.
Will you to come to our party tonight?
- Certainly.
Well, until then.
- Yes.
Ah, Klaus, not now.
Yeah, sure, OK.
- It makes me nervous.
Yes, but not very much.
So cheer up.
The royal couple landed at 11.05...
in a private plane
at Tempelhof airport.
Empress Farah wore a fox-fur coat
and a black and white hat.
Stefan!
The Shah inspected an
honour-guard of the Berlin Police.
Stefan, dear friend.
Fresh off the presses.
OK.
For all to hear.
My clever star-journalist wife...
wrote an open letter
to her imperial highness Farah Diba.
Don't make a big deal of it.
- It'll be in the next edition.
5000 of these fliers are
already at the universities.
Very good.
Good day, Mrs Pahlevi. There's a story
in the New Review about life in Iran,
about how hot it gets there,
and how you, like most Persians,
like to holiday on the Caspian coast.
Like most Persians?
Isn't that an exaggeration?
Most Persians are farmers,
and make less than 100 Marks a year.
And half of all Persian
mothers die giving birth.
From hunger, poverty and illness.
And the children work
14-hour days weaving carpets.
Do most of them really holiday
with you at the Caspian seaside?
They write:
"The Shah must have a son. "
Iranian Law is
very strict on that point.
Strange that it seems so
unimportant to the Shah.
And no official statement is made.
That the Minister of Justice
makes no comment.
That unofficial courts
are held in secret.
That torture is allowed
under Persian law.
We do not want to insult you.
But the German public
should not be insulted
with crap like this
story in the New Review.
Faithfully,
Ulrike Meinhof.
Welcome, Pahlevi!
- Princess, Princess!
Farah! Farah Diba!
Murderer!
Are they crazy?
Are you crazy?
What are you doing?
Don't push me, you wanker!
Stop!
Is there a doctor here?
Let us through!
It's out of control here.
Are you stupid? There, the woman!
Can you help us?
We have an injured person here.
What happened?
He was attacking me.
- You are mad?
Let's go.
He needs a physician!
Mrs Meinhof, they were not on
the demonstrators' side. Why?
The right-wing press blamed
the disaster on the students.
Above all the Springer group
tried, in its newspaper,
to label the students as rioters.
"To shout is no longer enough,
now they want blood. "
But the truth is,
the protest proved that
we live in a Police state.
That the Police and the press
went too far in Berlin on June 2nd.
And that the only freedom
here is for the Police.
But Mrs Meinhof, with all respect...
- We all know that Kurras...
...who shot Ohnesorg, will be acquitted.
That is pure demagogy!
That is demagogy.
In America they discuss using
nuclear weapons in Vietnam,
and Israel starts a war of
aggression with the help of the USA.
which is called "preventive war" here.
- Israel has to defend itself.
Then Hitler's attacks on Poland
and Russia were also "preventive".
But you can't say that!
- Mrs Meinhof, I must say...
You must also consider the child.
This woman has nothing worthwhile to say.
The American Imperialist
machine will not stop!
Vietnam, Bolivia and now the Near East.
America has supplied
Israel with weapons for years.
Each warplane, each rocket,
each tank, everything comes from the USA.
Or the western industrial nations.
- They are not the people's friends!
The pigs want to control the
oil fields of the Near East.
It's just shit to them if
many thousands of people die.
I must now go to church.
- You should preach...
that over half the people in the world
do not have enough to eat.
Is it senseless to
preach for a better world?
That those condemned once again must resist!
You should get married soon.
Ulrike! Wait!
Wait!
Finally.
Hello, Baby.
- Well, Kitty?
So, here it is.
I hope it's enough.
Will it be enough?
- Why?
So...
- Hey!
I think... we don't want to
torch the department store
We need hard action to show
that wanker that we're not kidding!
And if people are still inside?
- Don't talk like a homo, Tussi.
Who'd be there at night?
And if there is: a bigger headline!
Are you insane?
- Andreas knows what he's doing.
You're under arrest!
- Police! Halt!
Idiot!
- Police!
Handcuff them!
- You're under arrest for arson.
Good morning.
Under continuous bombardment
by American warplanes...
of alleged Vietcong positions,
civilian populations suffer the most.
In the USA, particularly at
universities, these pictures led...
the students to rise up in protest.
In the Federal Republic...
thousands of students protest,
such as these, in Berlin.
The Anarchist Rudi Dutschke
mobilizes the resistance.
Comrades, we don't have much time.
In Vietnam the bombs fall every day.
We must stand up for them.
As Che said: It is not a matter of
wishing success to the victim of aggression,
but of sharing his fate.
One must accompany him
to his death or to victory.
From German ground...
From German ground
wars are still prepared.
From German ports and miltary bases...
The American military
wages the Vietnam war!
We cannot allow this!
We must stop the German government
helping this Imperialist war in Viet Nam!
Are you Ulrike Meinhof?
- Yes.
We are forced to take illegal action...
let sabotage and blockades start now!
We protest against this conference!
Ladies and Gentlemen,
this conference is terminated!
Are you Rudi Dutschke?
Yes, I am.
- You dirty communist pig!
I am dead. Let me live.
Father. Mother.
Soldier... Soldier...
He's down here!
He went down here somewhere.
Search the building site.
- Covering!
You are surrounded!
Come out with hands up!
I can't stand communists.
Rudi Dutschke is in critical condition
after two hours of emergency surgery today.
Only one of the two bullets
could be removed from his head.
Spontaneous demonstrations
have sprung up across the country,
blaming the Springer publishing house
for inciting the assasination attempt.
Springer, Murderer!
I didn't think this was your style!
Attention, this is the Police!
You are trespassing
on private property.
Leave the area immediately!
Come along!
Frau Meinhof? What are you doing here?
Release her. Frau Meinhof is a journalist.
Dresden!
Hiroshima!
Vietnam!
Dresden!
Hiroshima!
Vietnam!
Che Guevara was captured...
and then murdered by the CIA...
Yesterday Martin Luther King
was assasinated...
...Senator Robert Kennedy was shot...
Republican Richard Nixon becomes
the 37th President of the USA
Soldiers sealed off the street
and fired into the crowd.
One of the first Soviet vehicles
into Czechoslovakia...
The students call the protests
in Paris cultural revolution.
The state calls it anarchy.
The more I hear of this shouting,
the clearer it becomes - we need
to ensure the rule of law in this country.
In agreement with Andreas Baader
I want to make a statement.
He and I placed the bomb
in the department store.
We did it to protest
against the indifference...
of people who sit and watch
the genocide in Vietnam.
We believe that speech
without action is wrong.
Order, please!
Mr Mahler?
Could you do us the honour of
allowing the court to share the joke?
The judges can hardly understand
the ideas Ms Ensslins and Mr Baader.
Otherwise they would take off their
robes and join the protests themselves.
Order!
Order, please!
Mr Ensslin, your daughter wanted to
address your generation with her act.
Whatever they wanted to do,
it comes to this:
Our generation experienced,
in the name of the people,
concentration camps, Jew hate, genocide,
and now will not permit
reformation, a new beginning.
How do you explain that,
with the world as it is?
It's amazing that Gudrun, who considers
things very rationally and intelligently,
by one foolish act, experienced
a holy self implementation.
I feel that she created
something free with her act.
Even in the family.
I feel liberated.
Of a tightness and a fear,
that had ruled my life before.
It took the fear from me.
Throw a single stone,
and that is a crime.
Throw a thousand stones
and that is a political action.
Set fire to a car,
that is a crime.
Burn a thousand cars,
and that is a political act.
Protest is saying:
"I disagree with this and that. "
Resistance is saying:
"I will put a stop to this and that. "
Thanks for making this possible.
- It's OK. I've read your work.
Can one stop the genocide in Vietnam by
burning down a department store?
No. It was an error,
as I said in court.
It was an act of rebellion.
But it was pointless...
while Fascism grows
as strong as it was under Hitler.
This time we offer resistance.
Out of responsibility before history.
People, here and in America,
must eat. Must eat and buy.
But they do not think
about it, they just consume.
We wanted them to
think about it a little.
So you burned down
a department store?
I will never resign myself
to doing nothing. Never.
If people try to murder us,
like Ohnesorg und Dutschke,
then we will shoot back.
That is only consistent.
Do you really mean that?
All over the world
comrades fight with guns in hand.
We must become soldiers.
- We fight already.
And if the fascists throw
you into prison for it?
Such victims they'll have.
Or do you believe that you'll change
something with your grand theory?
Sorry, I didn't mean to be cruel.
Is Baader or Gudrun here?
- Gudrun is up there.
Oh! Sorry!
- Hello. Who are you?
I'm Peter Boock.
- And I'm Gudrun.
Are you a runaway?
Youth Training Centre.
- There are others here, too.
They'll soon come and join us.
They gather up here.
Can I bathe afterwards?
- Bathe now.
No water wasting here.
Tell me about yourself.
Where did you get that?
- Youth Training Centre. Lucky City.
I heard about it.
You nearly burned the place down.
The bastards nearly
beat us to death for it.
If they catch me,
no more day leave till I turn 21.
Don't let it worry you.
You're part of our family now.
You were locked up for arson, too.
But we are free on appeal.
And at least we can make an appeal.
And so we make it.
- And if they find me?
Andreas and I must disappear,
if our appeal is rejected.
Tell me... do I see right?
You trying to fuck my old lady?
Well, Kitty?
Hey.
Andreas, this is Peter.
What happened to you?
- The staff at Lucky City.
Then we should tear them some new arseholes.
Great leather jacket!
Here, it's yours.
Let's go! To Darmstadt!
- We don't have enough cars.
Then we'll steal two or three.
Only the gun cures the rigidity.
Go on, fire at will!
Fire at will!
We have made
extraordinary efforts...
to understand what the people want.
We want more democracy.
These words of the new Federal Chancellor
Willy Brandt as he takes office...
reconcile the students and end
nearly 3 years continuous riots.
The reform promises to create
peace at the universities, and the basis
to bring the outside parliamentary
opposition into the democratic process.
And what do you believe?
- I think the worst is over.
The protest movement
has lost its momentum.
Groups which feel existentially oppressed
will not hesitate
to bomb whatever parts of
society they see as oppressive.
Over here!
Can't you see us?
Gudrun?
Andreas... Hallo, Astrid.
- Mister Counsellor.
And? What are your plans?
What's next for you?
Can't you talk normally? Do you
really think Interpol are after us?
...because those jerks
in Frankfurt rejected our appeal?
We're not going back to prison.
Then come to Berlin. Illegally.
We're building up a new group.
We're further along than you'd think.
What have your guys done?
A lot's happened since you've been away.
We have good contacts.
Houses, ID, money, weapons.
We can provide everything.
Yeah, under your leadership.
The illegal underground attorney.
I'm shitting myself.
- Let him finish.
They couldn't steal grandma's puppy!
- That's not the point.
Where's Dutschke now?
- Living in London.
He's crippled, can hardly speak.
Since he was shot, nobody leads
while the struggle goes on.
The struggle would have been won,
if they hadn't screwed it up.
Show us what you're made of.
Steal the purse from granny's bag.
Baby...
- I want to know if he's got the balls.
Or is it all just talk?
Oh, man!
Fucking shit, they're stealing my car!
Hey! Stop!
Fucking spagetti-muncher!
Shit! You dumb bitch,
you left the car open again!
So what? Steal a new one.
- You CUNT!
CUNT! FUCK IT ALL!
WHY?
What are you doing here? Why us?
So call the cops.
Where's Ulrike?
- In bed.
Where's the bedroom?
- Back there.
Wait a minute.
Quiet, you'll wake the children.
We're back.
They're hunting you, you know.
- Big deal.
Can we stay here for a while?
- Yes, of course.
We're recruiting here
in Berlin. And in other cities.
We're expanding the group.
Political conditions change.
What are your plans?
- What kind of stupid question is that?
We take action.
If it goes wrong, too bad.
So, that's it for me.
Where can I crash?
I'll join you in a moment.
What does he mean, though?
- He means exactly what he said.
Andreas does not compromise.
You must understand that.
Andreas is more of a revolutionary
than all the rest of us together.
Sounds great when you're stoned.
You look unhappy.
I saw a film about Youth Homes.
Girls there are treated like shit.
I thought I could do something
about it, but they remain shitty.
But Peggy there escaped.
What we need is a new morality.
You must see that clearly.
Draw a line between you and our enemies.
You must leave the system
and burn your bridges.
And your son?
That you may never see again?
If you're serious,
you have to be prepared to suffer.
Andreas also has a baby daughter.
I could never leave my children.
Shit.
Do you know how fast you were going?
- No. Do you?
Show me your license, please.
And the registration papers, please.
I'm sorry about this, officer.
My friend seems to have thrown them out.
You live in Rome, Mr Hoger?
- Yes.
Your date of birth?
- 14/6 nineteen...
'39.
You don't seem too sure about it.
- It was a long time ago.
And?
They're holding him in Moabit jail.
We have to get him out.
- I'll help.
Me too.
How? Tying sheets together?
You can write about it afterwards.
That's all you're good for.
Perhaps Andreas should
just serve the ten months.
Shit! Freeing Prisoners is
what we're always talking about.
We'll show the pigs what we can do,
if they lock up our people.
We're getting Andy out! Now!
We can't visit him in prison anyway.
You'll be a publisher.
We'll get in with a book contract.
Good day.
This is Dr Gretel Weitemeier,
who will be publishing our book.
Pleased to meet you.
- The pleasure's all mine.
Are you insane?
Man, it only fires tear gas.
Looks real though, eh?
Where did you get that?
- from Gudrun.
We've got a lot of things, now.
- And who is "we"?
I cannot say.
Well, I can:
Gudrun, Astrid, Ingrid.
I bought some Asprin.
- Ulrike.
She's only the decoy.
You told me you
wouldn't be involved!
What is your part? Well?
Mahler arranged for Andreas and I
to visit the Sociological Institute...
to research our book.
- They're allowing him out for that?
With a Police escort, of course.
- That's where we come in.
Inside the Institute,
we stick guns in the cops' faces...
and away runs Baader.
- And you?
I stand back and look surprised. That's all.
Now can we get on with dinner?
But you're all female.
What if they don't take you seriously?
Mahler knows some professionals.
We'll have help. Mahler says...
it'll be a piece of cake.
- I don't believe it.
The cops have real guns,
not like that piece of junk.
This is completely insane!
I have to go through with it.
Mr Baader, in the event of an
escape attempt, we are authorised to shoot.
I want to make sure you know that.
- You needn't worry about it.
I've seen you on TV.
- Hopefully I was interesting.
Yes, very. Anything else you need?
- Thanks, I'll manage.
Hey.
- Hey.
Sit down here.
Can I get a cup of coffee?
- Of course.
Are you married? Do you have any children?
- Yes, wife and child.
So, moving along. We have...
I told you yesterday,
come back after noon today.
The reading room is occupied.
- Then we'll wait here.
It's a long wait.
- We have time.
In the following discussion...
Go, quick. Let's move.
- What do you want here?
Shit!
Hands up!
- Up against the wall!
C'mon, Kitty!
Gudrun! Help me!
Stay down!
According to reports the kidnappers
shot the doorman with tear gas
They overpowered the guards
and released Baader by force of arms.
My God, the children!
Go, children, run.
Quickly.
We say: The uniform-wearer
is a pig, not a human.
And so we treat it as such.
We will not negotiate with them.
It is wrong to talk
at all with these people.
And of course, they may be shot
when we consider it necessary.
The gun makes its statement.
It is possible,
in our actions, our enemies
may occasionally triumph.
But where it is important,
they will not beat us.
Our success will belong to history.
Welcome to the camp!
- The attorney looks like Fidel Castro!
Welcome, Andreas. Hi, Gudrun.
- Which way to Havana?
This is Achmed, the Commander.
This is Gudrun and Andy.
The men sleep here, the women there!
- What?
The rules of the camp.
- Shit on that. We sleep together! There!
What's Ali Baba saying?
- Forget it. Come.
It's all fine. Sleep where you like.
All in this house here.
Fucking shit!
This does not have
anything to do with our job!
We are urban guerrillas, understand?
We don't fight in the desert!
Tell that camel-jockey we
fight against bank guards!
French.
What are they laughing about?
- We're just admiring your trousers.
You've got them a little dirty.
I'll finish you off, you cocksucker.
Baby, leave it.
he's one of us.
He is not one of us.
He's only here because he's
scared of the cops in Germany.
SICILY
You're homesick, right?
Which means you give up.
- These people are fighting a war...
What does our situation
in Germany have to do with it?
You can't force a revolution
there, even with a Kalashnikov.
Germany is just one front.
We fight with comrades everywhere
against injustice and oppression.
I thought you knew that.
- And what about your children?
You live underground.
Why bring them into it?
Sooner or later it'll come out that
I did not participate in the Baader escape.
Then I can go back legally.
I could take care of the children.
That sounds very much like betrayal.
Betrayal? Of whom?
Look after yourself.
What now? Can't we have a little fun?
He won't give us any more ammunition.
- Then we go on strike.
What are they staring at?
- Probably never seen naked women before.
Hey, look who's here.
What does one do with a traitor?
People's court.
What?
He asks us to get dressed.
- Why should we?
Sexual freedom and the fight
against imperialism go together.
He doesn't understand, Baby.
Fucking and shooting are the same!
Abu Hassan is commander
of the whole camp.
Don't worry...
...we'll bring you out.
Hands up!
Don't move!
Get down on the floor!
This is a hold-up!
Get away from the window!
Get down!
In West-Berlin today, a gang robbed
three different banks in 10 minutes.
In Breitenbach Platz, three
masked men and one woman.
At 8.10 AM four men dressed in parkas...
The robbers got away with
approximately 200,000 Marks.
It is believed that the robbers
are militant left-wing extremists.
Detectives found a bag of
ski-masks dumped by the bandits.
They left handbills with the text
"Expropriate from enemies of the people".
217,449.50 Marks.
Not bad for 10 minutes work.
- Ulrike should write a statement.
Make clear that we only
took the money of capitalists.
That only the rich need be worried.
- Yeah, liberal wankers think that's good.
Stupid whore! Can't you
be careful? Shit-for-brains!
And so was the revolution made!
Some say,
Bank robbery is not political.
Revolutionaries in Latin America
call bank robbery "expropriation".
Official Statement
on Bank robbery.
It is politically
right to expropriate.
It is strategically right,
if it finances the revolution.
Your children are gone.
I just heard from Sicily.
The man who took them
even knew the code word.
They're surely already
with your ex, the old fascist.
The Baader-Meinhof group will become
accepted as leaders of the revolution.
What are you doing there?
That's my car!
Yesterday five arrests were made:
Attorney Horst Mahler,
student Peggy Schönau...
In the young woman's handbag,
police found a Belgian pistol.
The charges: possession of guns,
falsification of identity papers,
car theft, burglary,
theft and armed robbery.
In Mühlheim, Dortmund, and Konstanz,
the prisoners face similar charges.
Show me your identity papers.
Get back!
...further threats of violence...
The trial of Astrid Berger began today.
According to a study by
the Allensbacher Institute...
25% of Germans under 30
are sympathetic to the RAF.
That's about 7 million people.
Which makes finding
them a lot more difficult.
Lobster soup.
So we plan to
computerise identity papers.
I'll explain by
giving you an example.
Underground terrorists naturally
hide their identities from authority.
Without the new ID card...
no bank account.
Now they'll find it hard
to rent somewhere to live.
Everything will require
the new cards. Gas, water, electricity.
In Frankfurt alone, 16,000
customers usually pay bills in cash.
We will no longer accept cash.
All customers will have to use their new ID.
No ID: no health care, either.
- And then?
Then we take it further. For example,
No ID: no driving license,
no child support payments.
If everyone has to have an ID,
the last handful who don't: suspects.
That is a mathematical certainty.
In the long term it does
nothing to smash heads.
Or, as some would prefer,
to cut heads off.
Not the police,
but political powers
resistant to change,
allow terrorism to develop.
That is my opinion.
Oh, and say hello to
the minister for me.
Shit!
Floor it!
Halt!
Freeze!
Hands up! You too!
Go! Go! Petra, go!
Drop your weapons!
Kiss my arse!
Stop, girl! Freeze! Hands up!
Hello, Werner. You're back early.
Excuse me, this is my house.
You said one night only.
Oh, you'll have your way.
We'll be gone tomorrow.
Well, then. Tomorrow.
...two people, a man and
a woman, ran a police roadblock...
What's wrong?
That's Petra's car.
The woman was killed
in the shootout that followed.
She opened fire when ordered
to lay down her weapon.
Shit.
This is war.
- Now we kill a pig.
Cold-blooded murder.
Obviously they're shooting to kill.
They'll be hunting us all now.
- We must attack the cops directly.
Shoot down their helicopters!
Blow up their stations!
That goes against our policy.
- I shit on the policy!
The armed fight against Imperialists...
is against the US military presence
in Germany and in West Berlin.
We need to re-think our stategies.
- Do you think we need better plans?
We need more safety precautions.
Actions in cities we
don't know well are unwise.
What happened to Petra must not re-occur.
- Fuck-ups like that...
are not caused by bad planning.
- It went wrong. It was a mistake.
Her mistake! Not the group's.
People must follow the plans.
It was not the group's fault!
The plans are all over the place.
Made up as we go along...
Nobody questions why they go wrong.
- You cunt!
Your idea of emancipation
is the freedom to shout at men!
Baby, you know that's nonsense.
General Daniel Chase,
Chief-of-staff at the Pentagon, explains:
The US Air Force
does not bomb...
targets south of 17 degrees latitude
"For the mass-murderers
of Vietnam...
West Germany and West Berlin
should not be safe bases.
They must know that their crimes
against the Vietnamese people...
have created bitter enemies.
That there is no place in the world
safe from attack by
revolutionary Guerilla units. "
Offical Statement on bombing.
"We demand an end to
the bombing of Vietnam.
We demand the withdrawal
of US troops from Indochina.
We demand an end to the
naval blockade of North Vietnam. "
Police minister Herbert
Schoner was shot dead.
Two shots, one in the heart.
Also wounded was 25-year old
Manfred Fichtner from Kiel.
...in Hamburg, policeman
Heinz Eckart was shot...
"We carry out attacks on
judge and state lawyers
in retaliation against them
for holding political prisoners.
We demand that these laws are repealed.
We have no other means
to enforce our demands.
Petra Schelm Brigade. "
Police headquarters in
Augsburg were attacked today.
Five policemen were injured.
An attack in Munich followed.
Experts are searching for
the remains of the explosive device.
The senior public prosecutor has
offered 10,000 Marks reward.
The car is being examined
by Federal Police specialists.
A bomb tore apart the car of
High Court Judge Wolfgang Buddenberg,
as his wife started the engine.
Judge Buddenberg ruled against
the Baader-Meinhof group.
His wife remains in hospital
with serious injuries...
but is out of intensive care.
Shit.
We need more grinders.
...there are roadblocks on all
streets near the city center.
Heavily armed police are everywhere
Axel Springer publishing house.
- A bomb will go off in 5 minutes time.
Evacuate the building.
- Who are you?
Is it the nutcase again?
- Please stop calling us.
Stupid pig!
We demand that Springer newspapers
stop publishing lies about
liberation movements of the third world,
particularly about the
movement to free Palestine.
Our actions will only cease
when our demands are met.
The Federal Government condemns these
attacks with indignation and abhorrence.
Federal Chancellor Brandt called
the attacks "cowardly and devious".
Springer accepted the risk
that the bomb threat was genuine
rather than lose profits
by evacuating their workers.
For capitalism,
profit is everything,
people, who create it, are dirt.
We are deeply sorry
that workers were injured...
What do you suggest?
They can see that the
government is under pressure.
We strike the water.
- Pardon?
When you strike the water,
the fish surface...
I need the entire police force,
detectives, uniformed, all of them.
For one day, under the command of the
Federal Bureau of Criminal Investigation.
But that would be...
That would be at least 130,000 men.
That's right.
And all the helicopters, too.
And to close the borders.
We hit the entire
Federal Republic in one day.
That'll drive the fish
up and into our nets.
Cars are being searched
all motorways and arterial roads,
causing long delays
at border crossings.
All available officials
in West Germany are taking part.
By noon today, police
in Hamberg checked 15,000 cars.
It's a police state,
just like you said.
The public supports these measures.
It's not looking
good for the Revolution.
Shut up! Urban guerrillas operate
in the rift between the state and the people!
Checkpoints have been set up at all
public buildings, airports, and sporting events.
Vehicles were searched. Photographs of
possible RAF members were distributed.
As Mao Tse-tung once said...
you've heard it before...
but I'll remind you today. He said:
"When the enemy slanders us,
that is good.
Because it proves,
that there is a clear
line between them and us.
When the enemy paints
us in the blackest colors,
that's better.
Because it shows,
that there is not only a clear
distinction between them and us,
but also that we have achieved
a great deal in our work. "
The container.
It's been moved.
That's not my powder.
Don't move! Police!
Freeze! Drop the gun!
Halt! Police!
Drop the gun!
Shit!
Throw your weapons
into the yard and come out!
The longer you wait,
the stronger our forces.
We have you surrounded.
There is no chance of escape.
Come out or we'll storm
the building. Why are you waiting?
I repeat:
Come out now.
You have no chance,
this is not a game.
Do you want to get out of this alive?
There is no chance of escape.
Your only chance is to surrender now.
If you come out with hands up,
nothing will happen to you.
We can wait all day.
We are in control here.
We control the entire area.
There is no way out.
Police searching for the Baader-Meinhof group
in Frankfurt this morning
achieved a major success
Beside Baader, Holger Meins was arrested,
which greatly weakens the leadership of the group.
Shit.
There, great Terrorist.
Shoot your way out.
That's for Norbert.
- And that's for Heinz.
Can I try it on?
- Changing room over there.
This way. That's the jacket.
No! No!
No! Help!
No! Fucking cops!
Let go! No!
Is that you?
Are you Ulrike Meinhof?
Silence.
I'm over here!
Here!
The Minister of the Interior
congratulates you on your great successes.
says the RAF is finished.
I now declare the 1972 Olympic Games open.
World record!
...in disguise, into the
the Israeli teams's lodgings.
...Israeli Coach Moshe Weinberg
was killed with two shots to the head...
The Black September group is
demanding the release of over 230 prisoners
...in exchange for the release of the hostages.
If the prisoners are not released
the hostages will be killed...
Our worst fears have
become bitter reality.
With the terrible events of the past week...
at The Munich Olympics,
all of our hopes for peace...
have come crashing down.
We cannot remove all the hatred
and violence from this world
We must be prepared to fight
the forces of evil.
Gentlemen,
our duty is to fight terrorism.
And, if possible, to end it.
Tell me your ideas.
We need a special force,
to shut down these lunatics.
Strong words don't
work against terrorists.
A special-purpose force
is absolutley crucial.
But those measures alone
will not solve the problem.
The roots lie deeper.
- Namely?
The Israeli occupation of Palestine.
Nobody pays attention to that.
So the terrorists try to
force the world to pay attention.
So you approve of their aims?
- Nadler, don't talk rubbish.
I never said that.
However,
one must understand their motives.
So, you allow these
murderers a special status?
No! But we can't
fight such forces rigidly.
And our ignorance promotes terrorism!
It's true,
but the question is...
whether terrorism
is the new form of war.
Whether it replaces conventional war,
which does not take place any more.
I don't follow you.
What about the victims?
Or their loved ones?
- I understand your anger.
But our duty is to fight terrorism.
And to do that we must understand
the problems of the third world.
The Middle East conflict, the Vietnam war.
Understand these problems objectively!
It feels like an explosion in the head.
Like the cell is full of pressure.
The one feeling
I can't supress. Rage.
The is no release from the pressure.
That's the worst thing about isolation.
The clear knowledge that one
does not have a chance of survival.
Today we begin a hunger strike.
We demand change to
one of the prison conditions:
Equal conditions for political
prisoners to all other prisoners.
A hunger strike is our only way...
to resist in solitary confinement.
The hunger strike is to show
that we will not compromise.
We expect explosions
in the prison system.
The goals must be
set out so that each Rocker,
so everyone, does not
lose their sense of purpose.
That is, so that
they do not break us.
We can say: Each 3rd week,
or each 2nd or 4th week, whatever...
one of us will die.
And so on, until the isolation,
until the torture for all is waived.
But the hunger strike will only work
if we all stick to it together
Until our demands are met.
Even if some of us die.
Counsellor, just a few minutes.
The prisoner is very much weakened.
Gudrun wrote to me.
This is our goal. You decide it,
when you die. Freedom or death.
Just in case,
if I pass from this life,
It's murder.
If the pigs keep this up, it's murder.
Do not believe the lies of murderers.
Get me a cigarette.
I don't know what will
happen, I should die.
If I'm killed.
What next?
That's it.
Which side is right?
It's not so clear.
The final battle to free
mankind from the pigs.
The revolutionary struggle.
With love for life
and with contempt for death.
I serve the people.
Get the prison doctor here, now.
- But it's the weekend.
Then get his assistant.
- We don't have one.
Then call in an outside doctor.
- We're not authorized.
He's dying in there!
Get a doctor! Now!
Unfortunately, we can't do a thing.
One day after the death of Holger Meins,
of the Baader-Meinhof Group,
who died while on hunger strike,
Berlin Chief Justice Drenkmann
was shot dead in his home.
We do not shed tears for Drenkmann.
We are pleased by his execution.
...attacks on judges and lawyers
who prosecuted the Anarchists.
Lawyers for Holger Meins today
launched a wrongful death action...
It was necessary, because
each judge and cop must know...
that they will be held
responsible for their deeds.
That's Rudi Dutschke.
Holger, the fight goes on.
The trial of Baader and the others
begins in 4 weeks, here in Stammheim.
The pictures are of the
security wing on the 7th floor.
The prisoners will be kept here.
- Men and women together?
Indeed, they demanded it.
- Outrageous.
So they will cooperate during the trial.
- We provide a terror center!
It's important that
the trial goes smoothly.
We of the Federal Police can
monitor the group's communications.
And we most certainly will.
Go! Go!
Everyone out! Go!
The German Embassy in Stockholm
was occupied by terrorists today
They threaten to kill hostages
unless their demands are met.
The terrorists have released
a statement to the German government.
Eye-witnesses reported shots.
The police closed off the area.
About 100 People reportedly
remain in the embassy.
Emergency units are treating
those who escaped the building
A caller claiming to be a member
of the RAF demanded the release...
Authorities believe the attack
is a last desperate attempt...
to demand the release of RAF prisoners
in Stammheim before the trial begins.
No fire in the cell!
- Kiss my arse. We're leaving.
...will shoot one hostage every hour.
Storm the building and
we blow up it. We leave only...
if our demands are fulfilled.
Withdraw or they blow it up!
They refuse to withdraw.
- Then we prove we're serious. Translate.
I am von Mirbach, Military Attaché.
They will shoot me...
if you do not withdraw.
- Leave! Leave now!
The first explosion
occurred shortly before midnight.
In minutes the whole building was
in flames, while the terrorists dug in.
The explosions
followed each other closely...
as police stormed the burning building.
The hostage drama, which ended
last night in explosions and gunfire,
has claimed at least three lives,
two of them embassy staff.
Among them was Heinz Hillegaart,
chief of the catering department.
It is still unclear whether he was shot,
like Military Attache von Mirbach,
or whether he died in the explosions.
The 3rd death was one of the terrorists.
Five terrorists were arrested:
Siegfried Hausner, Bernhard Rössner,
Karl-Heinz Dellwo, Lutz Taufner
and Hanna Krabbe.
What a shitty action.
Shitty action!
The Swedish government delivered
the captured terrorists to Germany.
Today the severely wounded
Siegfried Hausner was flown to Stammheim.
I'll hold you responsible!
If the prisoner dies,
he'll be, after Holger Meins,
the second to die in our custody.
With such incompetence we'll
give the RAF another martyr!
This is a prison. We're not
equipped for severely wounded people!
We must keep him here. Orders.
- That's completely insane.
The two public defenders
are sufficient for Mr Baader.
If he doesn't want them, too bad.
They do not defend me.
They never even spoke with me!
Incidently, someone has written
"head off" beside my microphone.
Beside my microphone it says "head off"!
What do you think it means?
I don't know what it means.
I am unable to take part in this trial.
I am not nearly able,
in this place, at this time,
I cannot say what...
I mean... I can't tell...
I request an examination for us,
by an independent physician.
Rejected.
They say we're not isolated,
because we have slightly larger cells.
I say: We were,
up till a short time ago,
completely isolated for the last 3 years!
Our only human contact was
through a tiny slot in the cell door.
Someone stood behind the door and wrote.
- I rule you out of order!
Why do you change my notes
suddenly, without explanation?
Because that things
you write have no power.
There's no need to do that.
You jump on my errors
and go on and on about it.
I could write a book on
your foolishness. Guard!
Your tired act,
I'm sick of it.
I've had my fill of this.
You're driving me crazy!
Really, I don't get it.
What's their problem, the bitches?
It's the last straw that
they allowed Hausner to die.
They're not fooling anyone.
- You're a bullshit revolutionary!
We have to get out of here.
It's not easy to recruit
new troops after Stockholm.
You argue with your emotion,
you shitty egoist! You have no clue!
Not a clue! Piss off!
Piss off, arsehole!
Get us out of here, you sow!
Get us out of here!
Sow! Arsehole!
Get us out of here, you sow!
Mrs Meinhof, you are obliged to remain.
The accusations against you stand.
You can't force me, arsehole.
I decide that, "arsehole" or not.
It's about time you admitted it.
The accused is today excluded,
Because she called
the chairman an "arsehole".
Then you also exclude me.
- That's not for you to decide!
Does it come to physical force?
- Sit! Sit down in your place.
Go on with your ridiculous procedure.
I'll disturb it so long as I'm here.
Do we really need to hear it?
I'll say it too:
You're a fascist arsehole!
We can't defend ourselves
so we refuse to participate.
Old sow.
You... you are deranged!
Did I hear you
call me an "old sow"?
Did I hear that right,
or am I mistaken?
I want it to be carefully noted!
And you, Mr Baader,
You called me a
"fascist arsehole".
Filthy rat.
The defendants are excused.
This court
adjourns for consulation.
Ulrike, how is she? Very dark.
A Vampire, trembling with bloodlust.
Ulrike tries to laugh,
it doesn't work.
Necrophile. Hysteric.
Really absolutely ugly me.
Although I still say
my reason hasn't left me.
It's separate from me.
This is shit.
She gives me false information.
Gudrun transcribes it wrong.
Why do you do that?
Is it because you want to torment me?
I return the agony.
An eye for an eye.
I don't look at it.
I can't bear it.
I am not a witch,
but I am sometimes brutal.
Don't pretend.
You hate us. It's obvious.
So stop eating, until you're
better, or go to the Devil.
How are we to attain our goals,
if we blow workers up?
Show the reports you wrote on us.
- I know, Springer was an error.
That went against our aims.
- We've discussed this a thousand times.
We've been through this! Many times!
- The action was counter revolutionary!
Real revolutionaries would
have shot you for that!
The question is:
How can an isolated prisoner...
make the authorities recognise
that his behavior has changed? How?
In isolation, the prisoner can't
show that his behaviour has changed.
There's only one possibility.
And that is betrayal.
The prisoner in isolation
has no other chance.
So there are two possibilities.
I will speak now!
A prisoner can be silent,
and die,
or a prisoner can talk.
That is confession and betrayal.
And based on this fact,
the Federal High Court resolution
makes a clear and definite statement.
That is torture.
Designed to force confessions.
To confuse, demoralise, and punish.
You're the knife in the back of the RAF.
Because you never learn.
It is mysterious,
if I say I can't bear it?
I don't bear it any more.
That is what I can't bear.
We are responsible for the
attacks on CIA headquarters...
on the 5th US Corps in Frankfurt
and on US headquarters in Heidelberg.
We are also
responsible for the bombing
of the Springer building.
Beyond that, we have no knowledge.
We had no part in the planning
or the execution of any other actions.
The Anarchist Ulrike
Meinhof took her own life.
She was found dead this morning
in her cell in Stuttgart-Stammheim.
Ulrike Meinhof, that was murder!
The 41-year-old hung herself with
a towel tied to the window bars.
There will be an autopsy later today.
The 109th day of the hearing in Stammheim
was unusually crowded this morning.
The court-appointed defense
counsels made a request...
to adjourn the trial for 10 days.
To investigate whether Ulrike
Meinhof really committed suicide.
We believe Ulrike was executed.
We don't know how, but we know who.
Chief Federal Prosecutor Buback said:
"The State protects those
who support the State.
Herold and I always find a way. "
- These defamatory remarks...
It was a coldly conceived execution!
Like Holger Meins and Siegfried Hausner!
The execution of Ulrike now!
Fascist! Murderer!
- Silence!
Under your jurisdiction as judges
two prisoners out of five were killed!
Why were Schubert, Möller
and Mohnhaupt brought to Stammheim?
The public prosecutor's office gave in
to the pressure of public opinion.
I allowed it, in order
to prevent further suicides.
Baader und Ensslin...
RAF prisoners were allowed
to transfer to Stammheim.
Time's up! Return to your cells!
- Stop eating.
Mohnhaupt will be free in 7 Months.
Those jerks guaranteed it.
Baader and Ensslin
probably insisted on it.
Lovely to see you.
Are you Charlie?
I want to talk with him alone.
Andreas and Gudrun trust you.
- How are they?
They're shitty! We must
get them out of there, soon.
Before they end up
like Ulrike und Holger.
A few think we should hijack
a 747 and circle it over Bonn.
With an ultimatum to exchange
our people in 6 to 8 hours.
Then let it fall.
In the middle of Bonn.
We heard of that plan. No.
No actions against the people.
We stick with the kidnappings.
How far advanced are you?
Ready to go.
Here, before I forget it...
I brought this for you.
Nearly 5 years prison...
- It's a long time.
That's how long since I fucked a guy.
They need weapons.
If another escape attempt fails...
They want to be able to make a choice.
You must not mention it
to the others. No matter what happens.
Very pretty, the medal.
- Very much.
Congrats!
You work on your honour day?
Gottfried Hagemann. You remember,
the lawyer. With his arrest...
We found coded
operational plans on him.
Big arsehole.
HM Auschecken. Margarine.
What is your conclusion?
Siegfried, we're expecting an
act of revenge against you.
On 7.4.77 the Kommando Ulrike Meinhof
executed Chief Federal Prosecutor Buback.
Siegfried Buback was directly
responsible for the murder of Holger Meins,
Siegfried Hausner, and Ulrike Meinhof.
As Chief Federal Prosecutor,
he ordered their murders.
Under Bubacks regime,
Holger on 9.11.74.
was murdered by starvation.
Under Bubacks regime,
Ulrike on 9.5.76.
was illegally executed,
in a faked suicide by hanging.
Under our laws, for which
Ulrike fought, justice was done.
We will not allow our
comrades to be murdered,
We will show the authorities that
when prisoners continue to fight,
killing them will not solve the
problem. Kommando Ulrike Meinhof.
We could not protect him.
- I ask myself:
Why do new terror units always
develop? What motivates them?
A myth.
Come on in,
Mr Ponto is expecting you.
Thanks.
You brought a whole committee.
- I wanted to show them your place.
My friends. Klara.
- Good day.
Gerd.
- Herr Ponto, shall I stay?
No, you may go.
Come outside.
What a lovely surprise.
I'll be with you in a moment.
I'll put those in a vase. Sit down.
Klara.
Go to the exit. Come along.
- Are you mad?
You are a prisoner of the RAF.
Go, get out!
I didn't want that!
How do I explain to my parents?
We agreed, no guns! And only a tap
on the head, if he resists.
We wanted to kidnap him!
- Why are you here?
To play the female Robin Hood
without getting your hands dirty?
You crybaby! You sign the claim
of responsibility. - No! Never!
On the execution of Ponto, we say:
It is a clear warning to those types.
If you wage war on the people,
then war will be waged on you.
Susanne Albrecht,
soldier of the RAF.
The door stays open!
We do not accept locked doors!
Hey! No locked doors!
Now you'll have the war you wanted!
You pigs! You filthy pigs!
Let me go. Idiot.
Fucking shitty cops!
You wanker! Fucking leave her alone!
You sow! Let go!
How much longer?
- Soon. Nearly done.
229, 12th line, 4th word.
9, 10, 11, 12... 3,4.
Finished.
We forestalled our
planned liquidation.
We retain our identity.
"We know there is a
concrete plan to kill us.
Surrender is impossible.
You must hurry.
We do not need to say more. "
That is clear. If we do nothing,
they've given us straight facts.
What "straight facts"?
- It's very clear, OK?
If we don't get them out
immediately, they're dead.
Now what?
- Schleyer goes on vacation tomorrow.
For how long?
- Several weeks.
Then let's do it
tomorrow. Why not?
We'll have to do it the hard way.
- What's that mean? Hard?
It means we shoot the escorts,
all of them, to get to Schleyer.
The SEK are armed and trained.
It'll be a combat situation.
The driver isn't SEK, though.
- You miserable wanker!
The prisoners will be murdered!
- Stop it!
Let's get our plan in order.
- I can't do this.
I can't be a part of this.
- OK. Then you better leave now.
We need to discuss plans.
They don't concern you any more.
Brigitte, you can't do this.
If you're captured again...
I am in charge here.
We'll discuss that later.
Now let's find out who's
willing to do it the hard way.
What about you?
It's safe to assume...
that Schleyer is being held
within 20 km of the scene.
Less than two hours ago it happened.
Five weeks after the
murder of the banker Ponto...
an assassination attempt
on Hanns Martin Schleyer.
Four police officers from
the escort were killed.
The search for
the attackers continues.
Schleyer is not among
the dead. It is obvious...
that the terrorists
have kidnapped him.
The manhunt goes on.
All the official parties
condemned the attack on Schleyer.
Now you have a problem.
Now you have a big problem!
Their reign of terror has not yet ended.
And they are feeling triumphant now.
But they must make no mistake.
...the Siegfried Hausner Kommando...
has taken the president of the employers
association, Hanns Martin Schleyer, prisoner.
The will of the German people is not broken.
They're sealing us in!
- They're doing what?
A Lufthansa airliner has been hijacked.
The aircraft was en route from Majorca
to Frankfurt, but was diverted to Rome.
86 passengers, mostly
Germans, are on board.
...footage of kidnapped
businessman Hanns Schleyer...
reading a statement from his captors...
You can see my current circumstances.
The government in Bonn
must make a decision.
The actions of the German goverment
prove that they are the terrorists.
The state, which claims to promote freedom...
...uses the methods of totaliarianism...
in the name of fighting terrorism.
I Have, so far, been
treated well by my captors...
Pressure on the
government is growing...
as the hijackers demand the
release of political prisoners...
including the RAF
prisoners in Stammheim.
As the hijack drama continues...
...reported to have
shot the pilot...
...threatened to kill one
passenger every 5 minutes...
The Pope has sent a plea for
the release of the passengers.
At Aden airport,
passengers and crew...
...swap for prisoners...
...have arrived in Cairo...
...prisoners in his country will be...
...emergency landing!
Baader Meinhof Gang terrorists who
are also holding Hanns-Martin Schleyer...
...passenger swap in Dubai.
...do not condone the
actions of political gangsters.
Comrade, they turned us down.
And where does that leave us?
Everything's gone wrong! Everything!
They've taken off again.
One pilot shot.
The plan was to stay in Aden.
What does it mean?
Baby. This thing is complete bullshit.
...landed in Somalia yesterday.
The body of pilot Jürgen
Schumann was dumped...
...before taking off again.
We cannot intervene, even if...
we could actually speak with them.
We do not approve of
killing innocent civilians.
The Federal Government,
unlike ourselves,
goes too far, is too violent.
I want to see the prison chaplain.
Whatever happens, it's not our doing.
Our policies are far more measured.
Do you really believe that?
Last month, 8 children
were left fatherless.
We have no control over
the actions of those outside.
We will be judged by
generations to come.
If Schleyer escapes, good.
I'm tired of it.
I wish to request...
materials to make a will.
The full legal documents, if possible.
And I'd like some help
in filling it out properly.
But Miss Ennslin...
With that done, I will
no longer fear my fate.
But surely you don't feel
that you are in danger?
I could die at any time.
You know what is going on outside...
that they're trying
to get us out of here.
That fight has international dimensions.
What are you getting at?
I ask you this:
Wouldn't they prefer
to see me vanish?
Many states would want that.
In Western industrial countries
the power structures...
are not so secure that they would wish...
to encourage a new wave
of resistance groups to develop.
What is your influence
on the current situation?
Free us, and the current
actions will be successful.
Would the government
want that to happen?
The judges and the politicians,
they want to avoid
that at all costs.
Miss Ennslin, I hope
we can continue to meet.
Farewell, father.
We have just recieved confirmation...
the Luftahansa terrorist
hijacking has ended...
with all of the 86
passengers safely rescued.
A spokesman for the Ministry
of the Interior has confirmed...
that a German anti-terrorist
squad stormed the plane last night.
The Bonn government
has issued a statement...
"... refused to release
the jailed terrorists. "
...these brutal actions
have not suceeded. "
- Good morning.
Mr Raspe.
Miss Möller. Miss Möller.
Alive.
Miss Ennslin.
The pigs really did it.
They killed all of them!
- Enough.
But they killed them all!
- Open murder!
They sacrificed themselves.
The time was not right.
What? Are you joking? What do you mean?
They were at risk.
Get them out immediately! Immediately!
Those were your words.
They knew the risks.
They had their alternatives.
They made their choices.
What happened was their own doing.
And Ulrike?
Her, too.
I think they recognised...
that the end had come.
Belgian - French border